<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rambles of a Technologist in Business</title><link>https://www.rajwadkar.us/</link><description>Recent content on Rambles of a Technologist in Business</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rajwadkar.us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>https://www.rajwadkar.us/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.rajwadkar.us/about/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-me"&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.rajwadkar.us/img/hs-mmr-b3-2.jpg" alt="This is me" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend most of my time working with early-stage companies and ambitious teams who are trying to turn sharp ideas into durable businesses. My interests span health, education, transportation, and infrastructure, but I care less about a specific sector and more about whether there is a real problem, a thoughtful model, and a team that can execute. Over the years, this has meant countless conversations about go‑to‑market, pricing, fundraising, and what it actually takes to build something that lasts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Open Source Designs and EDA</title><link>https://www.rajwadkar.us/post/opensourceeda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.rajwadkar.us/post/opensourceeda/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A majority of the IC designs are proprietary and confidential and are owned by the major players in the market. In the recent years there has been resurgence in Open Source IP, the most notable being the &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/"&gt;RISC-V&lt;/a&gt; processor, which is a great thing as the low power processor market has practically become a monopoly of the &lt;a href="https://www.arm.com"&gt;ARM&lt;/a&gt; processor. This post is a collection on various resources which are open source and free to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Garage Sale</title><link>https://www.rajwadkar.us/contact/garagesale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.rajwadkar.us/contact/garagesale/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years I have collected a number of things and am looking to get rid of them
If you find anything interesting let me know&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Vagabond</title><link>https://www.rajwadkar.us/post/vagabond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.rajwadkar.us/post/vagabond/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had studied this poem by R. L. Stevenson when I was in high school, it was my favorite and is a great source of
inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.poetryloverspage.com/poets/stevenson/vagabond.html"&gt;The Vagabond @Poetry Lovers Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Louis_Stevenson"&gt;Robert Lewis Stevenson @wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carpool for School in 2018-19</title><link>https://www.rajwadkar.us/contact/schoolpool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.rajwadkar.us/contact/schoolpool/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a carpool for 2018-19 school year for our daughter&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ducati : Giovanni Gavetti</title><link>https://www.rajwadkar.us/post/ducati/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.rajwadkar.us/post/ducati/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Ducati Case Study&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; by &lt;a href="https://store.hbr.org/search.php?search_query=Giovanni%20Gavetti&amp;amp;section=product"&gt;Giovanni
Gavetti&lt;/a&gt;,
focuses on the turnaround and strategic repositioning of Ducati, an Italian
maker of high-end sport motorcycles, and describes the current concerns with
the growth prospects of the company. Federico Minoli, the CEO and strategic
mind behind the turnaround, knew that Ducati could not grow indefinitely in its
current niche. One alternative was to attack Harley Davidson&amp;rsquo;s niche with a
Ducati interpretation of a cruiser.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VLSI Design</title><link>https://www.rajwadkar.us/post/vlsiinfo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.rajwadkar.us/post/vlsiinfo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the good old days of the last century and early this century I used to run a small blog
or a resource page about VLSI (Very Large Scale Integrated) circuit design and resources.
The domain was pretty new in the time and there were very little resources available at the time.
The technology is developing fast, however the industry is commoditized and disaapearing to the east.
The &lt;a href="http://mayursvlsiinfopage.blogspot.com/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; is still hosted on blogspot but I have stopped maintaining it. This post summarizes some of its relevant content which may still be useful for folks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>