<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rambles of a Technologist in Business</title>
    <link>https://www.rajwadkar.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rambles of a Technologist in Business</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rajwadkar.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Vagabond</title>
      <link>https://www.rajwadkar.net/post/vagabond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rajwadkar.net/post/vagabond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Blog is still under heavy contruction&amp;hellip;  I hope to go live soon in Aug 2019 In the meantime I have my old blog all  summarised in this one post here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had studied this poem by R. L. Stevenson when I was in high school, it was my favorite and is a great source of
inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.poetryloverspage.com/poets/stevenson/vagabond.html&#34;&gt;The Vagabond @Poetry Lovers Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Louis_Stevenson&#34;&gt;Robert Lewis Stevenson @wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLSI Design</title>
      <link>https://www.rajwadkar.net/post/vlsiinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rajwadkar.net/post/vlsiinfo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Blog is still under heavy contruction&amp;hellip;  I hope to go live soon in Aug 2019 In the meantime I have my old blog all  summarised in this one post here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the good old days of the last century and early this century I used to run a small blog
or a resource page about VLSI (Very Large Scale Integrated) circuit design and resources.
The domain was pretty new in the time and there were very little resources available at the time.
The technology is developing fast, however the industry is commoditized and disaapearing to the east.
The &lt;a href=&#34;http://mayursvlsiinfopage.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;  is still hosted on blogspot but I have stopped maintaining it. This post summarizes some of its relevant content which may still be useful for folks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ducati Case Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.rajwadkar.net/post/ducati/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rajwadkar.net/post/ducati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Blog is still under heavy contruction&amp;hellip;  I hope to go live soon in Aug 2019 Io
n the meantime I have my old blog all  summarised in this one post here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ducati Case Study&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;1&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.hbr.org/search.php?search_query=Giovanni%20Gavetti&amp;amp;section=product&#34;&gt;Giovanni Gavetti&lt;/a&gt;, focuses on the turnaround and
strategic repositioning of Ducati, an Italian maker of high-end sport
motorcycles, and describes the current concerns with the growth prospects of
the company. Federico Minoli, the CEO and strategic mind behind the turnaround,
knew that Ducati could not grow indefinitely in its current niche. One
alternative was to attack Harley Davidson&amp;rsquo;s niche with a Ducati interpretation
of a cruiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis below tries to answer the following questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the fundamental logic behind Minoli’s actions to turn Ducati around?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the underlying economic logic of Minoli’s turnaround?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can Ducati sustain its current growth in the sports segment? Can key competitors take counter actions to reduce Ducati’s growth prospects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are Minoli’s strategic options in 2001?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which would you recommend? (I expect you to back your recommendations with hard data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
